in this case we have a network which has
an input on the left-hand side usually
you have the input on the bottom side or
on the left they are pink in my slides
so if you take notes make them pink not
just kidding
and then we have what how many
activations how many hidden layers do
you count there four hidden layers so
overall how many layers does the network
have here
six right because we have four hidden
plus one input plus one output layer so
in this case I have two neurons per
layer right so what does it mean how
what are the dimensions of the matrices
we are using here two by two so what
does that 2 by 2 matrix does come on you
have you know the answer of this
question rotation yeah then scaling then
sharing and reflection fantastic right
so we constrain our network to perform
all the operations on the plane we have
seen the first time if I allow the FIR
the hidden layer to be a hundred neurons
long we can Wow okay we can easily we
can affect our fantastic what is it we
are watching movies now I see see a
fantastic what is it mandalorian is so
cool now ok ok how nice is this lesson
is even recorded ok we have no idea ok
give me a sec ok so we go here done
listen all right so we started from this
network here right which we had this
intermediate layer and we forced them to
be two-dimensional right such that all
the transformations are enforced to be
on a plane so this is what the network
does to our plane it folds it on
specific regions right in those folders
for
folding are very very abrupt this is
because all the transformations are
performing the 2d layer right so this
training took me really really a lot of
effort because the optimization is
actually quite hard whenever I had the
hundred neuron into a hidden layer that
was very very easy to train this one
really really took a lot of effort and
you had to tell me why okay if you don't
know the answer right now better you
know the answer for the midterm so you
can take note of what are the questions
to the meter right so this is the final
output of the network which is also that
2d layer to the embedding so I have no
non-linearity out my last layer these
are the final classification regions so
let's see what each layer does this is
the first layer affine transformation so
it looks like it's a 3d rotation but
it's not right it's just to be a
rotation reflection scaling and shearing
and then what is this part ah what's
happening right now you see all we had
like the video part which is killing all
the negative sides of the network right
sorry all the negative sides of this
space right it is the second affine
transformation and then here you apply
again the areevo
you can see all the negative subspaces
have been erased and they've been set to
zero then we keep going with a third
affine transformation it's zoom it zoom
in a lot and then again you're gonna
have now the redo layer which is gonna
be killing one of those all the three
quadrants right only one quadrant
survives every time and then we go with
the fourth affine transformation we
along gating a lot because again given
that we confine all the transformation
to be living in this space it really
needs to stretch and you know use all
the power it can write again this is the
second last then we had the last affined
transformation which is the final one
and then we reach finally linearly
separable regions here finally we're
gonna see how each a final summation can
be
a split in each component so we had
rotation we have now squashing like the
wind then we have rotation reflection
because the determinant is minus 1 and
then we had the final bias again you
have the positive part of the areeda
rectified linear unit again rotation
flipping because again we had a negative
a minus 1 determinant zoom in rotation
one more reflection and then the final
bias this was the second a fine
transformation then we have here the
positive part again we are third layers
or rotation reflection zooming and then
we have the SVD decomposition right you
should be aware of that right you should
know and then final is the translation
and again the third riddle then we had
the fourth layers or rotation reflection
because the determinant was negative
assuming again the other rotation icon a
small rotate after reflection and bias
finally read oh and then we had the last
the fifth layer so rotation zooming we
didn't have reflection because the
determinant was plus one again
reflection in this case because the
terminal was negative and then finally
the final bias right and so this was
pretty much how this network which was
just made of thickness of layers of
neurons that are only two neurons per
layer is being performing the
classification task and all those
transformation had been constrained to
be living on the on the on the plane ok
so this was really really hard to train
can you figure out why it was really
really hard to train what does it happen
if my if my bias of one of the five
layers put my points in away from the
top right quadrant exactly so if you
will have one of the four biases putting
my initial point away from the top right
quadrant then the videos are going to be
completely killing everything and
everything gets collapsed into zero okay
and so there you can't do any more or
anything
so this network here was really hard
again to train if you just make it a
little bit fatter than instead of
constraining to be two neurons for each
of the hidden layer then it much easier
to train or you can do a combination of
the two alright so instead of having
just a fat Network you can have a
network that is less fat but then you
have a few hidden layers okay
so that was pretty much yeah question so
the fatness is how many neurons you
helper hidden layer right okay so the
question is that how do we determine the
structure or the configuration of our
network right how do we design Network
and the answer is going to be that's
what the N is gonna be teaching across
the semester right so keeping keep keep
keep it like keep your attention high
because you know that's what we're gonna
be teaching here that's a good question
right there is no like mathematical rule
like there is a lot of experimental
empirical evidence and you know a lot of
people trying different configurations
we found something that actually works
pretty well now again we're gonna be
covering these architectures in the
following lessons other questions don't
be shy no okay so I guess then we can
switch the sort of second part of the
class okay so we're gonna talk about
commercial nets today and is that right
in so I'll start with something that's
relevant to commercial Nets but not just
which is the idea of transforming the
parameters of a neural net so here we
have a diagram that we've seen before
except with a small twist the diagram
we're seeing here is that we have known
that G of X and W W being the parameters
X being the input that you know makes a
prediction about an output and that goes
into a cost function we've seen this
before but the twist here is that the
weight vector instead of being a
parameter that's being optimized is
actually itself the output of some other
function possibly parametrized in this
case this function is no parameterized
function or it's a branch wise function
but the only input is another parameter
you okay so essentially
what we've done here is made the weights
of that neural net the function of
someone inventory some more elementary
parameters you through a function and
you realize really quickly that that
caucus works there right if you back
propagate gradients for you know through
the the G function to get the gradient
of whatever objective function realizing
with respect to the white parameters you
can keep back propagating through the H
function here to get the gradients with
respect to you so in the end you sort of
you know propagating things like this so
when you're auditing you you're
multiplying the Jacobian of the
objective function with respect to the
parameters and then by the Jacobian of
the H function with respect to its own
parameters okay so you get the product
of two jacobians here which is the just
what you get from back propagating you
don't have to do anything in pi torch
for this as well happen automatically as
you define the network and and that's
kind of the old date that that occurs
now of course W being a function of U
through the function H the the change in
W will will be the change in U
multiplied by the Jacobian of H
transpose and so this is the kind of
thing you get here the effective change
in W that you get without updating W you
actually are dating you is the OData you
multiplied by the Jacobian of H and you
know we had a transpose here we don't we
have the opposite there this is a square
matrix which is n w by n W which is the
number of the dimension of W squared
okay so this matrix here has as many
rows as W has components and then the
number of columns is the number of
components of U and then this guy of
course is the other way around
so it's an u by n W so when you probably
make the product do the product of those
two matrices you get an N W
interview matrix and then you multiply
this by this NW vector and you get an NW
vector which which is what you need for
dating the weights okay so that's kind
of a general form of transforming the
parameter space and there's you know
many ways you can use this and a
particular way of using it is when H is
what's called a you know what we talked
about last week which is a it's a white
connector so imagine the only thing that
H does is that it takes one component of
U and it copies it multiple times
so that you have the same value the same
weight replicated across the G function
the G function we use the same value
multiple times so let's say this would
look like this so let's imagine you is
two dimensional u1 u2 and then W is four
dimensional but w1 and w2 are equal to
u1 and W 3 w 4 are equal to u2 so
basically you only have two free
parameters and when you're changing one
component of you changing two components
of W at the same time in a very simple
manner and that's called weight sharing
okay when two weights are forced to be
equal they actually afford they are
actually equal to a momentary parameter
that controls both that's where sharing
and that's kind of the basis of a lot of
ideas you know commercial Nets among
others but but but that that you can
think of this as a very very simple form
of H of U so again you don't need to do
anything for this in the sense that when
you have which sharing if you do it
explicitly with a module that does kind
of a white connection on the way back
when the ingredients are back propagated
the the gradients are summed up so the
gradient of some cost function with
respect to u 1 for example will be the
sum of the gradient so that consumption
with respect to W 1 and W 2 and
similarly for the gradient respect to u
2 would be the sum of the gradients with
respect to W 3 and W 4 ok that's just
the effect of that propagating through
the two white connectors
okay here is a slightly more general
view of this parameter transformation
here that some people have called hyper
networks so hyper network is a network
where the weights of one network are
computed as the output of another
network okay so you have a network H
that looks at the input it has its own
parameters U and it computes the weights
of a second network okay so the
advantage of doing this are these values
name for it the idea is very old goes
back to the 80s people using what's
called multiplicative interactions or
three-way network with signal PI units
and they're basically this idea and this
is maybe a slightly more general general
formulation of it that you have sort of
a dynamically your function that's going
to dynamically defined in in G of X and
W because W is really a complex function
of the input and some other parameter
this is particularly interesting
architecture when what you're doing what
you're doing to X is transforming it in
some ways right so the you can think of
W as being the parameters of that
transformation so Y would be a
transformed version of X and and the X I
mean the the function H basically
computes that transformation okay but
welcome back to that in a few weeks just
wanted to mention this because it's
basically a small modification of of
this right you just have one more wire
that goes from X to H and that's how you
get those hyper networks
okay so we're showing that's you know
the idea that you can have one parameter
controlling multiple multiple projects
50 parameters in another network and one
reason that's useful is if you want to
detect a motif on an input and you want
to detect this motif regardless of where
the peers okay so let's say you have an
input
sequence but it could be a cool you be
an image this case is a sequence
sequence of vectors let's say and you
have a network that takes a collection
of three of those vacu three successive
vectors this network G of X and W and
it's tried to detect a particular motif
of those three vectors maybe this is I
don't know the power consumption
electrical power consumption and
sometimes you know you might want to be
able to detect like a blip or a trend or
something like that or maybe it's you
know financial instruments of some kind
some sort of time series maybe it's a
speech signal and you want to detect a
particular sound that consists in three
vectors that define the the sort of
audio content of that of that speech
signal and so you'd like to be able to
detect if it's a speech signal and
there's a particular Sonya you need to
detect for during speech recognition you
might want to detect you know the sound
the vowel P right the the sound P
wherever it occurs in a sequence you
want some you know some detector that
fires when the sound P is is pronounced
and so it should like to have is
detector you can you can slide over
right and regardless of where this motif
occurs detected so what you need to have
is some sun networks and prioritize
function that you know you have multiple
copies of that function that you can
apply to various regions on the input
and they all share the same weight but
you'd like to train this entire system
and to n so for example let's say let's
talk about starting more sophisticated
scene here where you have let's see a
keyword that's being being pronounced so
the the system listens to sound and
wants to detect when a particular
keyword a wakeup word has been as been
pronounced right so this is Alexa right
and you say Alexa and exit wakes up it
goes bong right
so what you like to have is you know
some network that kind of takes a window
over the sound and then sort of keeps
you know in the background sort of
detecting but you'd like to be able to
detect you know wherever the sound
occurs within the frame that is being
looked at who's been listened to I
should say so you can have a network
like this where you have you know
replicated detectors they all share the
same weight and then the output which is
you know the score as to whether
something has been detected on that goes
to a max function okay and that's the
output and the way you train a system
like this you know you will have a bunch
of samples are you examples where the
key word has been pronounced and a bunch
of audio samples with the key word was
not pronounced and then you train a 2
class classifier turn on when a tech
size somewhere in this frame to an art
when it's not but nobody tells you where
the word lxl occurs within the the
window that you train the system on okay
because it's really expensive for
laborers to like look at the audio
signal and tell you exactly well this is
the word is Alexa is being pronounced
the only thing they know is that you
know within this segment of a few
seconds the word has been pronounced
somewhere okay so you'd like to apply a
network like this that has those
replicated detectors you don't know
exactly where it is but you run through
this max and you want to train the
system to you know you want to back
propagate gradient to it so that it
learns to detect you know Alexa whatever
wake up word occurs and so they are what
happens is you have those multiple
copies five copies in this in this
example of this network and they all
share the same weight you can see this
as just one weight vector is sending its
value to five different instances of the
same network and so we back propagate
back propagate through the to the five
copies of the network you get five
radians so those gradients get added up
for the parameter now this is a slightly
strange way this is implemented in pie
charts and other deep running framework
which is that this accumulation or
gradient in a single parameter is done
implicitly and it's one reason why
before you do a back project or
you have to zero add the gradient
because there's sort of implicit
accumulation of gradients when you do
back propagation okay so here's another
situation where that would be useful and
this is for really the real motivation
behind conditional Nets in the first
place which is the the problem of
training system to recognize the shape
independently of the position of whether
the shape occurs and whether there are
distortions of that shape in the input
so here this is a very simple type of
convolutional net that is has been built
by hand it's not being trained okay it's
been designed by hand and it's designed
explicitly to distinguish scenes from
genes okay so you can draw a C on the
input image which is you know very low
resolution and what this equation is
from these is that C's have n points
right there is the the stroke kind of
ends and you can imagine designing a
detector for that whereas these have
corners so if you have an endpoint
detector or something that detects the
end of a segment and a corner detector
wherever you have corners are detected
it's a C it's a D and whatever wherever
you have segments that end
it's a C so here's an example of over C
you take the first detector so the
little black and white would he's here
at the top is an endpoint detector okay
it's it detects the end of a of a
segment and the way this this is
represented here is that the the black
pixels here so think of this as some
sort of template okay you're going to
take this template are you going to
swipe it over the input image and you're
going to compare that template to the
little image that is placed underneath
okay and if it's to match the way you're
going to determine whether they match is
that you're going to do
products so you're gonna think of those
back in white pixels as value of plus
one or minus one say plus one for Greg
minus one for for white and you're gonna
think of those pixels also as being plus
one for blacks and minus one for white
and when you compute the dot product of
a little window with that template if
they are similar you're gonna you're
gonna get a large positive value with
that dissimilar you're gonna get a zero
or negative value or smaller value okay
so you take that little detector here
and you compute the dot product with the
first window of second window that we
know etc you shift by one pixel every
time for every location and you recall
the result and what you what you get is
this right so this is here the the
grayscale is an indication of the
matching which is actually the dot
product between the vector of formed by
those values and the vac and the the
patch of the corresponding location on
the input so this image here is roughly
the same size as that image - border
effects and which is you see there is a
whenever the output is dark there is a
match so when you see a match here
because this endpoint detector here
matches the you know the endpoint you
see sort of a match here at the bottom
and and the other kind of values are not
as dark okay
not as strong if you want now if you
threshold those those values you set the
output to plus one if if it's about the
special zero if it's below the threshold
you get those maps here to that the
threshold appropriately but what you get
is that you know this little guy here
detected a match at the two end points
of the see okay so now if you take this
map you saw me sum it up just add all
the values you get a positive number
that's a through threshold and that's
your C detector it's not a very good C
detector it's not a very good detector
of anything but for those particular
examples of C's
and maybe those these it will work
you'll be enough now for the D is
similar those other detectors here are
meant to detect the corners of the D
right so this guy here this detector as
you swipe it over the the input will
will detect the upper left corner and
that guy will detect the lower right
corner once you threshold you will get
those two maps where the corners are
detected and then you can sum those up
and the the detector will turn on now
what you see here is an example of why
this is good because that detection now
is shift invariance so if I take the
same input D here and I've shifted by a
couple pixels
and I ran this detector again it will
detect the motif wherever there here the
output will be shifted okay so this is
called equivalence to shift so the
output of that network is equivalent to
shift which means that if I shift the
input the output gets shifted but
otherwise unchanged okay that's
equivalence invariance would be if I
shift it into the output will be
completely unchanged but here it is
modified it just went inside the same
way as the input and so if I just sum up
the activate the activities in the
future Mads here it doesn't matter where
they occur my ID detector will still
will still activate right if I just
compute the sum so this is sort of a
handcrafted pattern recognizer that use
users local feature detectors and then
kind of sums up their activity and what
you get is an invariant detection okay
this is a very classical way actually of
building certain types of pattern
recognition systems going back many
years but the trick here what's
important of course what's interesting
would be to learn those those those
templates you know can we you know can
we view this as just a neural net and we
back propagate to it and we learn those
templates as weights of a neural net you
know after all we're using them to do
that product which are weighted sum so
you know basically the
this layer here to go from the input to
those so-called future maps that are
weighted sums is a linear operation okay
and we know how to back propagate
through that we'd have to use you know a
kind of a soft threshold value with
something like this here because
otherwise we can do back cause okay so
this operation here of taking the dot
product of a bunch of coefficients with
an input window and then swiping it over
that's a convolution okay so that's the
definition of a convolution it's
actually the one up there so this is in
a one dimensional case where imagine you
have an input X J so X indexed by the J
in the index you take a window of X at a
particular location I okay and then you
sum you do a weighted sum of the window
of the X values and you multiply those
by the weights W J's okay and the Sun
presumably runs over a kind of a small
small window so J here would go from 1
to I don't know 5 something like that
which is the case in the little example
I showed earlier okay and that gives you
one why I okay so take the first window
of five values of X computer weighted
sum with the weights that gives you y1
then shifts that window by one compute
the weighted sum of the dot product of
that window by the devil use that gives
you Y to shift again etc okay now
in fact in practice where people
implement and things like by torch there
is a confusion between two things that
mathematicians think are very different
but in fact they're pretty much the same
its composition and cross correlation so
in composition the convention is that
the the index goes backwards in the in
the window when it goes forwards in the
weights in cross correlation they both
go forward in the end it's just a
convention you know it depends on how
you lay you know
organize the data in your weights you
can interpret this as a convolution if
you read the weights backwards so
readers make any difference but for
certain mathematical property is a
convolution if you want everything to be
consistent you you have to have the the
J in the W having an opposite sign to
the J in the X so the two dimensional
version of this if you have an image X
that has two indices in this case I and
J you do a weighted sum over two indices
K and L and so you have a window a
two-dimensional window index by K and L
and you compute the dot product of that
window over X with the weight and that
gives you one value in y IJ which is the
the output so the the vector W or the
matrix W in this in the 2d version there
is obvious extensions of this to 3-d and
4-d etc is called a kernel it's got a
competition kernel okay
so clear I'm sure this is known to many
of you but so what we're going to do
with this is that we're going to
organize you know build a network as a
succession of coalition's where you know
you know regular neural net you have
alternation of linear operators and
point wise non-linearity in
convolutional nets we're going to have
an alternation of linear operators that
will happen to be compositions or
multiple collisions then also a point
where is non-linearity and there's going
to be a third type of operation called
pooling which is actually optional
before before I go further I should
mention that there are twists you can
make to this completion so one twist is
what's called a stride
so it's tried to do composition consists
in giving the window from one you know
from one position to another instead of
moving it moving it by just one value
you move it by two or three or four okay
let's call this tried of a convolution
and so if you have an input of a certain
length and so let's say you have an
input which is kind of a one-dimensional
and size 100 and you have a combination
kernel size five okay and you convolve
the this kernel with the input and you
make sure that the window stays within
the input of size 100 the output you get
has 96 outputs okay it's got the number
of inputs - the size of the kernel which
is 5 minus 1 okay so that makes it 4 so
you get 100 minus 4 that's 96 that's the
number of you know windows of size 5
that fit within this big input of size
now if I use this tried so what I do now
is I take my window f5 where I applied
the kernel and I shift it not by one
pixel but by 2 pixels or two values
let's say they're not necessarily pixels
okay the number of that points I'm gonna
get is gonna be you know divided by by
two roughly okay
instead of 96 I'm gonna have you know a
little less than 50 now 48 or something
like that the number is not exact you
can figure out in your head very often
when people run collisions in commercial
Nets they actually pad the completion so
they sometimes like to have the output
being the same size as the input and so
they actually displace the input window
past the end of the vector assuming that
it's padded with zeros usually on both
sides does it have any effect on
performance or is it just for
convenience if it has an effect on
performance is bad okay very nice
convenient that's pretty much here
answer the the assumption that's bad is
assuming that when you don't have data
its equal to zero so when you're
nonlinearities are you it's not
necessarily completely unreasonable but
it sometimes creates like funny border
effects you know boundary effects okay
everything clear so far right okay so
what we're going to build is a neuron
that
composed of those coalition's that are
going to be used as feature detectors
local feature detectors followed by
nonlinearities and then we're gonna
stack multiple layers of those okay and
the reason for stacking multiple layers
is because we want to build hierarchical
representations of the
of the visual world of the data it's not
conditional ads are not necessarily
applied to images they can be applied to
speech and all the signals they
basically can be applied to any signal
that comes to you in the form of an
array and I'll come back to on to the
the properties that this array has to
verify so what you want is why do you
want to build hierarchical
representations because the the wall
disk is compositional and I alluded to
this I think you the first lecture if
remember correctly the fact that you
know pixels assemble to form simple
motifs like oriented edges oriented
edges kind of assemble to form local
features like corners and T junctions
and things like that gratings you know
and then those assembled to form motifs
that are slightly more abstract the
those assembled to form parts of objects
and those assembled to form objects so
there is a sort of natural compositional
hierarchy in the natural world and this
natural compositional hierarchy in the
natural world is not just because of
perception visual perception is true at
a physical level right you know you
started at the lowest level of the
description you know you have elementary
particles and they form you know the
clump to form less elementary particle
and they come to form atoms and it come
to form molecules and molecules come to
form materials and materials you know
parts of objects and parts of objects
into objects and things like that right
or macromolecules or polymer polymers
and then you have this this natural
composition or hierarchy the world is
built this way and it may be why the
world is understandable right so this is
famous quote from Einstein that says the
most incomprehensible thing about the
world is that the world is
comprehensible and it seems like a
conspiracy that we live in a world that
we are able to comprehend but we can't
comprehend it because the world is
compositional and
you know it happens to be easy to build
brains in a compositional world that
actually can interpret compositional
world it still seems like a conspiracy
to me so there's a famous quote from
from a not that famous but somewhat
famous from a statistician at Brown
called Stu given and and he says you
know that sounds like like a conspiracy
like magic but you know if if the world
were not compositional we would need
some some even more magic to be able to
understand it and he the way he he says
this is the world is compositional or
there is a God
you need to appeal to superior powers if
the world was not compositional to
explain how we can understand it ok so
this idea hierarchy and local feature
detection comes from biology so the
whole idea of conversation that comes
from biology has been so inspired by
biology and what you see here on the on
the right is a diagram by Simon thought
with psychophysicists and did some
relatively famous experiments where he
showed that the the way we recognize
everyday objects seems to be extremely
fast so if you show you flash the image
of an everyday object to a person and
you flash one of them every 100
milliseconds or so you realize that the
the the time it takes for a person to
identify in the wrong sequence whether
there was a particular object let's say
Tiger is about 100 milliseconds so the
time it takes for brain to interpret an
image and recognize basic objects in
them is about 100 milliseconds the tenth
of a second right and that's just about
the time it takes for the nerve signal
to propagate from the retina
where you know image our form on the in
the eye to what's called the LGN lateral
geniculate nucleus which is a small you
know piece of brain that basically those
contrast enhancement and gain control
and things like that and then that
signal goes to the back of your brain v1
that's the primary visual cortex area in
humans and then v2 which is very close
to v1 there's a fold that sort of makes
v1 sort of right in front of v2 and
there is lots of wires between them and
then v4 and then the info temporal
cortex which is sort of on the side here
and that's where object categories are
represented so there are neurons in your
temporal cortex that represent you know
general generic object categories and
you know people have done experiments
with this where you know epileptic
patients are in hospital and have this
skull open because they we need to
locate the exact position of the source
of their epilepsy seizures and because
they have electrodes or the surface of
their brain you can show the movies and
then observe if a particular neuron
turns on for particular movies and you
show them a movie with Jennifer Aniston
and there is this neuron that only turns
on when Jennifer Aniston is there okay
it doesn't turn on for anything else as
far as we could tell okay so you seem to
have very selective neurons in the info
temporal cortex that react to its small
number of categories there's a joke kind
of a running joke in neuroscience of a
concept called the grandmother sale so
this is the the one neuron and you're in
for temporal cortex that turns on when
you see your grandmother regardless of
what position what she's wearing how far
whether it's a photo or not nobody
really really using this concept where
people believe in or distributed
representation so there is no such thing
as the grand as a cell that just turns
on for you grandmother
there are this collection of cells that
turn on for various things and they
serve to represent you know general
categories but the important thing is
that they are invariant to position size
illumination all kinds of different
things and the the real motivation
behind congressional Nets is to build
neural nets that are invariant to in
relevant transformation of the inputs
okay you can still recognize a C or D or
your grandmother regardless of the
position and to some extent the
orientation the style etc so this idea
that the signal only takes 100
milliseconds to go from the retina to
the four temporal cortex seems to
suggest that if you count like the delay
to go through every neuron or every
stage in that in that pathway there's
barely enough time for shoe spikes to
get through so there's no time for
complex recurrent connections you know
recurrent computation is basically a
feed-forward process it's very fast okay
and we need it to be fast because that's
a question of survival for us there's a
lot of for most animal you know you need
to be able to recognize really quickly
what what what's going on particularly
you know fast-moving predators or price
for that matter so that kind of suggests
the idea that you know we can do perhaps
we could come up with some sort of
neuron that architecture that is
completely feed-forward and still can do
recognition the diagram on the right is
from Garant and von essen so this is a
type of sort of abstract conceptual
diagram of the two pathways in the
visual cortex there is the ventral
pathway and the dorsal pathway the
ventral pathway is you know basically
the v1 v2 v4 IT hierarchy which is sort
of from the back of the brain and goes
to the bottom and to the side and then
the dorsal pathway kind of goes you know
through the top also towards the info
temporal cortex and there is this idea
somehow that the
ventral pathway is there to tell you
what you're looking at right the dorsal
pathway basically identifies locations
geometry and motion okay so there is a
pathway for what and another pathway for
where if you want and that seems fairly
separate in the human or primate visual
cortex and of course there are
interactions between them so various
people had the idea of kind of using so
what is that idea come from there is
classic work in neuroscience from the
late 50s early 60s by Rizzo
there on the picture here the one got
Nobel Prize for it so it's really
classic work and what they showed with
cats
basically by poking electrodes into cat
brains is that neurons in the in the cat
brain in v1 detect are only sensitive to
a small area of the visual field and
they detect oriented edges contours if
you want in that particular area okay so
the area to which a particular neuron is
sensitive is called a receptive field
and you take a particular neuron and you
you sure it kind of oriented bar if you
want that you rotate and at one point
the no one will will fire and as the for
a particular angle and as you move away
from that angle the activation of the
neuron kind of diminishes okay so that's
called orientation selective neurons and
when visual close simple cells if you
move the bar little bit you go out of
the receptive field that neuron doesn't
fire anymore doesn't react to it this
could be another known almost exactly
identical to it just a little bit you
know away from the first one that does
exactly the same function you will react
to a slightly different receptive field
but with the same orientation so you
start getting this idea that you have
local feature
detectors that are positioned replicated
all over the visual field which is
basically this idea of completion okay
so there are simple cells and then
another idea that or discovery that
Wiesel did is the idea of complex cells
so a complex cell is is another type of
neuron that integrates the output of
multiple simple cells within a certain
area okay so they will take different
simple cells that all detect contours at
a particular orientation edges at a
particular orientation and compare you
know an aggregate of all those
accusations they will either do a max or
a Sun or some a square or square root of
some square some sort of function that
does not depend on the order of the
arguments okay let's say max for the
sake of simplicity so basically a
complex cell will turn on if any of the
simple cells within its input group
turns on I said okay so that complex
cell will detect the negative particular
orientation regardless of his position
within that little region so it builds a
little bit of shift invariance of the
representation coming out of the complex
cells with respect to small variation of
positions of features in the input so a
gentleman by the name of cuckoo kunihiko
fukushima no real relationship with a
nuclear power plant in the late 70s
early 80s experimented with computer
models that sort of implemented this
idea of simple circle complex cell and
you had the idea of sort of replicating
this with multiple layers so basically
you know the oversize he did was very
similar to the one I showed earlier here
with this sort of handcrafted feature
detector some of those feature detectors
in his model were handcrafted but some
of them were around they were
an unsupervised method they were you
didn't have backdrop right back prop
didn't exist so I mean it existed but he
didn't it wasn't really popular and
people you know didn't use it so so he
trained those filters basically with
something that amounts to a sort of
clustering algorithm a little bit and
you know separately for each layer and
so he would you know train the filters
for the first layer train this with
Harrington digits he also had a dataset
of handwritten digits and then feed this
to complex cells that we kind of you
know pool the activity of simple cells
together and then that would consist
that would form the input to the next
layer and it would repeat the same
running algorithm his model neuron was
very complicated it was kind of inspired
by biology so we had separate inhibitory
neurons the the other neurons or you
know only have positive weights and I
growing weights etc we managed to get
this thing to kind of work okay
not very well but sort of worked then a
few years later I basically kind of got
inspired by similar architectures but
between them supervised with backprop
okay so that's the the genesis of
commercial nets if you want and then in
apparently more or less max reasonably
into the poachers lab at MIT he kind of
rediscovered this architecture also but
also didn't use backdrop for some reason
equals this H max
this is sort of early experiments I did
with commercial Nets when I was
finishing my postdoc in University of
Toronto in 1988 so that goes back a long
time and I was trying to figure out you
know does this work better on the small
data set so if you have a tiny amount of
data you're trying to fully connect to
network or linear network with just one
layer or network with local connections
with no shadow it or compare this with
what was not yet called accomplish on
that where you have shared weights and
local connections which one works best
and it turned out that in terms of
generalization ability which are the
curves on the bottom left the which you
see here the the top the top curve here
is basically the baby convolutional net
architecture trained with very simple
data set of handwritten digits that were
drawn with a mouse right we didn't have
any way of collecting images basically
at that time and then if you have real
connections without shared weights it
doesn't you know it works a little worse
and then if you have fully connected
networks it works worse and if you have
a linear network it not only works worse
but but it also over hits it over trains
so the test error goes down after a
while and this was trained with 320 320
training samples which is really real
all those networks add you know on the
order of five thousand connections 1000
parameters so this is you know a billion
times smaller than what we do today a
million times I would say and then I
think my postdoc I went to Bell Labs and
Bell Labs had you know slightly bigger
computers but what they had was a data
set that came from the Postal Service so
they had zip codes for envelopes and we
built a data set out of those zip codes
and then trying a slightly bigger a
neural net for three weeks and got
really results so this this commission
on that did not have separate Commission
and pooling it had
strided Commission so coefficients where
the window is shifted by more than one
pixel so that's what's a result of this
the result of this is that the output
map when you do a composition that where
the stride is is more than one you get
an output whose resolution is smaller
than the input and you see an example
here so here the the input is 16 by 16
pixels that's what we could afford the
columns are 5 by 5 but they are shifted
by 2 pixels every time and so the the
the output here is smaller because of
that
okay and then when you're later this was
the next generation comes from that this
one had separate commercial and pulling
so where's the premium operation at that
time the breeding operation was just
another neuron except that all the
weights of that neuron were equal okay
so a putting unit was basically you need
that computed an average of its inputs
and then cut I did a bias and then
passed it to a non-linearity which in
this case was a hyperbola tangent
function okay all the non-linearity is
in this network where hyperbola tangents
at the time that's what people were
doing and the printing operation was
performed by shifting the window over
which you compute the the aggregate of
the IP to the previous layer by by 2
pixels okay so here you get a 32 by 32
input input window convolve this with
filters that are 505 yeah I should
mention that a combination kernel
sometimes is also called a filter and so
what you get here are outputs that are I
guess minus 4 is 28 by 28 okay and then
there is a pooling which computes an
average of pixels here over a 2x2 window
and then shifts that window by 2 so how
many such windows do you have since the
image is 28 by 28 you divide by 2 is 14
by 14 okay so those images here are 14
by 14 pixels okay and they are basically
half the resolution as the previous
window because of this stride okay now
it becomes interesting because what you
want by is you want the next layer to
detect combinations of features from the
previous layer and so the way to do this
is you have different completion filters
apply to each of those feature maps okay
and you sum them up you send the results
of those full completions and you pass a
result through non-linearity and that
gives you one feature map of the next
layer so because those filters are 5x5
and those images are 14 by 14
those guys are ten by ten okay to not
have border effects so each of these
feature maps for which there are sixteen
if I remember correctly uses a different
set of kernels to convolve the previous
layers in fact the the connection
pattern between the feature map the
future wrapper this way you're on the
future mapper the next layer is actually
not full so not every feature mask
connected to every feature map is a
particular scheme of different
combinations of feature map from the
previous layer forming combining two for
future master the next layer and the
reason for doing this is just to save
computer time we just could not afford
to connect everything to everything it
would have taken twice the time to to
run for more nowadays were kind of
forced more or less to actually have a
complete connection between feature maps
in the commercial net because of the way
that multiple competitions are
implemented in GPUs
which is sad and then the next layer up
so again those maps are ten by ten those
feature maps are ten by ten and the next
layer up again is produced by putting in
subsampling
by a factor of two and so those are five
oh five okay and then again there is a
five oh five competition here of course
you can't move the window five by five
over five of our image so it looks like
a full connection but it's actually a
convolution okay keep this in mind but
you basically just only one location
okay and those feature maps at the top
here are really outputs and so you have
one spatial okay
because you want you can only place one
fiber five-window within a fiber 5 image
and you have 10 of those feature match
each of which corresponds to a
categories when you train the system to
classify digits from 0 to 9 you attend
categories this is a little animation
that I borrowed from aundrea Kapiti
spent the time to build this really nice
real animation which is the two
represents or multiple combinations
right so you have three feature mats
here on the input and you have 6
completion kernels and to feature maps
on the output so here the first group of
three feature mats are convolve with the
three input of three kernels are
involved with the three input feature
maps to produce the first group the
first of the two feature mats the green
one at the top okay and then and the
animation starts ok so this is the first
group of three Kaunas convolved with
this future mats and they produced the
green map at the top and then you switch
to the second group of of coalition
calls you've got you convolve with the
two input feature maps to produce the
map at the bottom ok so that's an
example of if I'm teaching upon the
input and feature an eye upon the output
and end times and composition kernels to
get all combinations
of animation which I made a long time
ago that shows commercial net after it's
been trained in action trying to
recognize digits and so what's
interesting to look at here is you you
have an input here which is I believe 32
rows by 64 columns and after doing six
compositions with six conversion kernels
passing it through a hyperbola tangent
non-linearity after bias you get those
sixty two maps here each of which kind
of activates for a different type of
feature so for example the feature map
at the top here turns on when there is
some sort of a horizontal edge this guy
here it turns on whenever there is a
vertical edge okay and those coefficient
kernels have been learning through back
pop the the thing has been just training
with with back prop no it said by hand
they said you know randomly usually so
you see this notion of equal variance
here if I if I shift the input image the
activations on the teacher mats shift
but otherwise stay unchanged
all right that's 50 quid variance okay
and then we go to the breeding operation
so this first feature mat here
corresponds to a putting a pooled
version of this first one the second one
to the second one third went to the
third one and the feeding operation here
again is an average then it is then a
similarly non-linearity and so if this
map shifts by one pixel this map will
shift by one half pixel okay so you
still have equal variance but you know
shifts are reduced by you know in fact
you have to essentially okay and then
you have the second stage where each of
those mats here is a result of doing a
convolution on each or a subset of the
previous maps with different kernels
summing up the resulting the results
were a sigmoid and so you get those kind
of abstract features here that are kind
of you know hard to interpret visually
but it's still equal value in two shifts
okay and then again you do prove
and subsampling so the pooling also has
you know this tried about a factor of
two so what you get here are or maps so
that those maps shift by one quarter
pixel if the input is by one pixel okay
so we reduce to shift and it becomes you
know might become easier and easier for
following layers to kind of interpret
what the shape is because you exchange
spatial resolution for future type
resolution you increase the number of
feature types as you go up the layers
the spatial resolution goes down because
of the pruning and subsampling but the
number of Chitra Maps increases and so
you make the representation a little
more abstract but less sensitive to
shift and distortions and the next layer
again performs completions but now the
size of the coalition kernel is equal to
the height of the image and so what you
get is a single band for this feature
map it's basically it becomes one
dimensional and so now the vertical
shift is basically eliminated right it's
turning into some variation of
activation but it's not it's not a shift
anymore it's some sort of simpler or
hopefully transformation of the input in
fact you can show it's simpler it's
flatter in some ways okay so that's the
sort of generic condition that
architecture we have this is a slightly
more modern version of it where you have
some form of normalization batch norm
good norm whatever if your kbank does
those are the multiple combinations in
signal processing vehicle filter banks
point where is non-linearity generally a
value and then some pooling generally
maximally okay in the most common
implementations of compliments because
of course imagine all the types of
proving I talked about the average but
the more generic version is the LP norm
which is you know take all the inputs
through a complex a little bit then to
some
power and then take the you know sum
them up and then take the little bit
that to one over the pallet
yeah this should be a sum inside of the
of the piece root here
another way to pool and again you know
any pruning up a good pruning operation
is an operation that is invariant to the
to a a permutation of the inputs it
gives you the same result regardless of
the order in which you put the input
here's another example we talked about
this function before one of the be log
some of our inputs of e to the X
exponential DX again that's a kind of
symmetric aggregation operation that you
can use so that's going to a stage and
accomplish on that and then you can
repeat that these sort of various ways
of positioning the normalization some
people put it after the non-linearity
before the pooling you know it depends
but it's typical so how do you do this
in pi torched there's no different ways
you can do it by you know writing it
explicitly writing a class so this is a
example of a complex on that class
particular one here when you do
completion value and and and Max fully
okay so the constructor here creates
coalition's coalition layers which have
parameters in them and this one has
what's called three connected layers I
hate that okay so there is this idea
somehow that the the last layer of a
convolutional net like like this one is
fully connected because every unit in
this layer is connected to every unit in
that layer so that looks like a full
connection but it's actually useful to
think of it as a convolution okay
for efficiency reasons or maybe some
others bad reasons they called you know
pretty connected layers they we used the
class linear here but it kind of breaks
the whole idea that your network is a
conditional network so it's much better
actually to view them as compositions in
this case one by one convolution which
is sort of a weird concept okay so here
we have four layers - compositional
layers and two so-called fully connected
layers and then the way we so we need to
create them in the constructor and the
way we use them in the four pass is that
you know we do a composition of the
input and then we apply the value and
then we do max pooling and then we run
the second layer and apply the value and
do max filling again and then we
initiate the output because we it's a
pretty connected layer so we want to
make this a vector so that's where the X
View - one does and then apply a value
to it and you know and this the second
free connected layer and then apply your
soft max if you want to do
classification and so this is somewhat
similar to the architecture you see at
the bottom the numbers might be
different in terms of you know feature
maps and stuff but but the general
architecture is it's pretty much what
we're talking about yes this again you
know whatever bred in descent decides we
can look at them but if you train with a
lot of examples or natural images the
kind of filters you will see that the
first layer basically will end up being
mostly oriented edge detectors very much
similar to what people - what no
scientists observe in in the context of
animals individual contacts of animals
the will change when you train the model
that's the whole point
yes okay so it's pretty simple here's
another way of defining those this is I
guess it's kind of a outdated way of
doing it right
not many people do this anymore but it's
kind of a simple way also there is this
class in invite torch called
and then sequential and it's basically a
container and you keep putting modules
in it and it just you know automatically
kind of use them as being kind of
connected in sequence right and so then
you just have to call you know forward
on it and and and it will just it will
just compute the right thing in this
particular form here you pass it kind of
a bunch of pairs it's like a dictionary
so you can give a name to each of the
layers and you can later a kind of
access them
it's the same architecture we're talking
about earlier yeah I mean the the
backdrop is automatic right you you get
it by default you just called backward
and it knows how to back propagate to it
well the class kind of encapsulates
everything into you know into an object
you know where the parameters are
there's a particular way of sort of you
know getting the parameters out and and
kind of feeding them to dog feeding them
to an optimizer and so the optimizer
doesn't need to know what your network
looks like it just knows that there is a
function and there is a bunch of
parameters and it gets a gradient and
you know it doesn't need to know what
your network looks like yeah you'll
you'll you'll hear more about this
[Music]
tomorrow okay so here's a very
interesting aspect of congressional nets
and it's one of the reasons why they
where they've become so successful in in
many applications it's the fact that if
you every that you're in a commercial
net as a convention so there is no cool
connection so to speak you don't need to
have a fixed size input you can value
the size of the input and the network
will varied size accordingly because
when you apply a convolution to an image
you fit it an image of a certain size
you do a composition with the kernel you
get an image whose size is really you
know related to the size of the input
but you can change the size of the input
and it just changes the size of the
output and this is true for every
college every a conditional like
operation right so if your network is
composed only of convolutions and it
doesn't matter what the size of the
input is it's going to go through the
network and the the size of every layer
will change according to the size of the
input and the sum of the output will
also change accordingly so here is a
little example here where you know I
want to do cursive handwriting
recognition and it's very hard because I
don't know where the letters are so I
can't you know just have a character
recognizer that
I mean a system that will first cut the
word into two letters letters R and then
apply the conditional net to each of the
letters so the best I can do is take the
converse on that and swipe it over the
input and then record the output okay
and so you would take that to do this
you would have to take the course on
that like this that has a window large
enough to see a single character okay
and then you take your input image and
you compute your neural net your
commercial net at every location
shifting it by one pixel or two pixels
or four pixels or something like this
you know a small enough number of pixels
that we got less of where the character
occurs in the input you will still get a
score on the output whenever it used to
recognize one but it turns out that will
be extremely wasteful because you will
be entering the same competition
multiple times and so the proper way to
do this and this is very important to
understand is that you don't do what I
just described where you have a small
commercial net that you apply to every
window what you do is you take a large
input and you apply the combinations to
the input image since its larger you're
gonna get a larger output you cry the
second layer composition to that or the
pooling whatever it is you're gonna get
a larger input again etc all the way to
the top and whereas in the original
design you were getting only one output
now you're going to get multiple outputs
because you know it's a compositional
layer this is super important because
this way of applying a convolutional
nets with a sliding window is much much
much cheaper than recomputing the
commercial method every location okay
you wouldn't you would not believe how
many decades it took to convince people
that this was a good thing
so here's an example of how you can use
this this is a this is a conventional
net that was trained on individual
digits 32 by 32 it was trying on a list
okay 32 by 32 input Windows it's loaded
5 so it's very similar to the
architecture I just showed the code for
okay it's trained on individual
characters to just classify the
character in the center of the image and
the way was trying to said there was a
little bit of data augmentation where
the character in the center was kind of
shifted a little bit in various
locations changed in size and then there
were two other characters you know kind
of that was gonna add it to the side to
confuse it okay in many samples and then
it was also trained with a 11th category
which was none of the above and the way
it's trained is either you shoot a blank
image when you shoot an image where
there is no character in the center with
our characters on the side okay so that
it would detect when whenever it's in
between two characters and then you do
this thing of you know computing the
commercial net at every location in the
input without actually shifting the
commercial net but just applying the
convolutions to the entire image and
that's what you get so so here the input
image is 64 by 32 even though the
network was trained on 32 by 32 with
those kind of generated examples and
what you see is the activity of some of
the layers here not all of them are
represented and what you see at the top
here those kind of funny shapes you see
threes and fives popping up and they
basically are the dedication of the
winning category for every location
right so the the the 8 the 8 outputs
that you see at the top are basically
the output question into eight different
positions of the 32 by 32 input window
on the input shifted by 4 pixels every
time and what is
presentin is the winning category within
that window and the grayscale indicates
the score okay
so what you see is you know there's two
detector is detecting the five until the
three kind of starts overlapping and
then two detector is detecting the three
that kind of move around because you
know within 32 left 32 we go the three
adheres to the left of that 32 by 32
window and then to the right of that
other 32 by 32 windows shifted by 4 and
so those two detectors detect that 3 or
that 5 so then what you do is you take
all those scores here at the top and you
do a little bit of post-processing very
simple and you figure out it's a 3 and a
5 and what's interesting about this is
that you don't need to do prior
segmentation so something that people
had to do before in computer vision was
if you wanted to recognize an object you
had to separate the object from his
background because the recognition
system you know we get confused by by
the background but here with this
commercial net it's been trained with
overlapping characters and it knows how
to tell them apart and so it's not
confused by characters that overlap I
have a whole bunch of those on my web
website by the way those animations from
the early nineties know that there was
an issue that's one of the reasons why
you know computation wasn't working very
well it's because the very problem of
figure one separation detecting an
object and recognizing it is the same
you can't recognize the object until you
segment it but you can segment it until
you recognize it it's the same for
cursive handwriting recognition right
you can't so here's an example we have
pens
doesn't look like we have pens right oh
here we go that's true I'm sorry maybe I
should use the if this works
oh of course
okay
hey you guys read this okay
I mean that's it's horrible handwriting
but it's also because you know I'm
writing on the screen okay now can you
read it
minimum yeah okay you know where you can
segment the letters out of this right I
mean it's kind of random number of waves
but just the fact that the two eyes are
identified then it's basically not
ambiguous at least in English so that's
a good example of you know the
interpretation of individual objects you
know depending on their context and what
you need is some sort of high-level
language model to know what words are
possible if you don't know English or
similar languages that have the same
word there's no way you can you can read
this spoken language is very similar to
this so we all of you who have had the
experience of learning a foreign
language probably have the experience
that you have a hard time segmenting
words from a new language and then
recognizing the words because you don't
have the vocabulary right so if I speak
in front sees your comments about your
phone say whenever you need a was
already need mo except if you speak
French so I said let's focus on tense
its words but you can tell the boundary
between the words right because it is
basically you know key a seizure between
the words unless you know where the
words are in advance right so that's the
program of segmentation you can't
recognize until the segment you can
segment until you recognize you have to
do both at the same time and you know
early computer vision systems are really
really hard time doing this
so that that's why you know this this
kind of stuff is big progress because
you don't have to do segmentation in
advance it just just train your system
to be robust to kind of overlapping
objects and things like that yes in the
back yes there is a bug run class so
when you see a blank response it means
the system says none of the above
basically right so it's been trained to
produce none of the above either when
the input is blank or when there is one
character that's too you know outside of
the center or when you have two
characters there's nothing in the center
or when your two characters are
overlapped but there is no central
character right so it's you know trying
to detect boundaries between characters
essentially here's another example so
this this is the this is an example that
shows that even a very simple commercial
net with just two stages right coalition
pooling coercion pooling and then two
layers of you know two more layers
afterwards can solve what's called a
future banding problem so visual
neuroscientists and computer vision
people had the the issue there was it
was kind of a puzzle how is it that we
perceive objects as objects you know
objects are collections of features but
how do we bind all the features together
of an object to form this object is
there some kind of magical way of doing
this and and they did you know
psychologists did experiments like you
know
draw this and then that and you perceive
the the bar as a single bar because
you're used to bars being you know
obstructed by occluded by other objects
and so you just assume it's an occlusion
and then there are experiments that you
know figure out like how much do I have
to shift the two bars where to kind of
make me perceive them as two separate
bars but in fact you know the minute
they perfectly line and if you if you do
this you know exactly identical to what
you see here but but now you perceive
them as two different objects so you
know how is it that we do the we seem to
be solving the future bonding problem
and what this shows is that you don't
need any specific mechanism for it it
just happens if you have enough
nonlinearities and you train with enough
data then as a side effect you get the
system that solve the future binding
problem without any particular mechanism
for it so here you have two shapes and
you move a single
stroke and you know he goes from the 601
to a 3 to a 5 and a 1 to a 7 & a 3 etc
[Music]
right good question so the question is
how do you distinguish between the two
situations we have two fives next to
each other and the fact that you have a
single fight being detected by two
different frames right two different
framing of of that five well there is
this explicit training so that when you
have two characters that are touching
and none of them is really centered you
train the system to say none of the
above right so it's it's always going to
have you know five blank five it's all
it's always gonna have even like one
blank one even the ones can be very
close it will you'll tell you the
difference okay so what are common is
good for so what you look at is this so
every now your here is a convolution
okay including the last layer so it
looks like a full connection because
every units in the second layer goes
into the outputs but in fact it is a
convolution it just happens to be
applied to a single location so when I
imagine that this failure at the top
here now is bigger okay which is
represented here okay now the size of
the kernel is the size of the image you
had here previously but now it's a
convolution that has multiple locations
right and so what you get is multiple
outputs that's right that's right each
of which corresponds to you know
classification over an input window of
size 32 by 32 in the example I showed
and those those windows are shifted by 8
by 4 pixels the reason being that the
the network architecture I showed here
has a combination which tried one then
pruning which tried to composition which
tried one pudding which tried to
stride is for right and so to get a new
output you need to shift the input
window by for two to get to get one of
those because of the the tool putting
layers with and maybe I should be a
little more explicit about this let me
draw a picture that would be clearer so
so you have an input like this
you didn't really complement let's say
combination of size three okay yeah
asteroid one ok I'm not I'm not gonna
draw all of them then you have playing
with subsampling sighs - so you pull
over - and you know so let's try this -
so you shaped by - no overlap
okay so here the input is this size one
two three four five six seven eight
because the combination is of size three
you get an output here of size six and
then when you know pulling with
subsampling of whist tried to you get
three outputs because you that divides
the output by two okay
let me add another one actually two okay
so now the output is 10
this guy is eight this guy is four
I can't do cognitions now also let's say
three only get two I only get two
outputs okay
oops hmm not sure way it doesn't draw
doesn't to draw you one that's
interesting aha
it doesn't react to clicks that's
interesting
okay
oh sure what's going on Oh sure is not
responding
all right I guess it crashed on me
well that's annoying
yeah definitely crashed and of course
you forgot it so okay so we're ten then
eight because of competition with three
then we have putting of size two with
stride tune so we get four then we have
competition with three so we get two
okay and then maybe putting again sighs
- and so simply until we get one okay so
ten input eight four two and then one
for the pooling this is condition three
you're right this is two and those are
three etc right now let's assume I add
15 units here okay so that's going to
add let's say four units here two
minutes here then
[Music]
yeah this one is like this and like that
so a good four and I get another one
here okay so now I had I had only one
I'd put in by adding four four inputs
here which is not 14 I've got two
outputs why for because I have to stride
of - okay so the overall subsampling
ratio from input to output is 4 it's 2
by 2 times 2 so now this is 12 and this
is 6 and this is 4 so that's a you know
a demonstration of the fact that you
know you can increase the size of the
input it will increase the size of every
layer and if you have a layer that has
size 1 and the it's a compositional
layer that it's size is going to be
increased yes
change the size of a letter like you
vertically horizontally yeah so there's
gonna be so first you have to train for
it if you want the system to have so
many variants to size you have to train
it with characters of various sizes you
can do this with the documentation if
you saw if your characters are
normalized that's the first thing second
thing is empirically simple conditional
Nets are only invariant - sighs - within
a factor of Rogersville factor like you
can increase the size by you know maybe
40 percent or something I mean change
the size about 40 percent plus minus 20
percent - something like that right
beyond that you you know you might have
kind of more trouble getting invariance
but people are trained with like you
know input input
I mean objects of sizes that vary by a
lot so the way to handle this is if you
want to handle variable size is that if
you have an image and you don't know
what size the objects are that are in
this image you apply to accomplish on
that to that image and then you take a
second
resisted by a factor of two to scale the
image by a factor to run the same
condition that on that new image and
then reduce it by a factor of two again
and run the same Congress on that again
on that image okay so the first
condition that we'll be able to detect
small objects within the image so let's
say your network has been trained to
detect objects of size I don't know 20
pixels like faces for example right
there are 20 pixels it will detect faces
are roughly 20 pixels within this image
and then when you search sample by a
factor of 2 and you apply the same
network it will detect faces that are 20
pixels within within the new image which
means there were 40 pixels in the
original image okay which the first
network will not see because you know
the face would be bigger than its input
window and then the next network over
will detect cases that are 80 pixels etc
right so then by combining the scores
from all of those and doing something
called on maximum suppression you can
actually do detection and localization
of objects people use considerably more
sophisticated techniques for detection
now and for localization that we'll talk
about next week but that's the basic
idea so let me conclude what our colony
is good for they're good for signals
that come to you in the form of a
multi-dimensional right but that
multi-dimensional array has to have two
characteristics at least the first one
is there is strong local correlations
between values so if you take an image
random image take two pixels within this
image two pixels are on your body those
two pixels are very likely to have very
similar colors okay take a picture of
this class for example two pixels on the
wall basically of the same color okay it
looks like there is a ton of object here
but animate objects but in fact most
means statistically your neighboring
pixels are essentially the same color as
you move the distance from two pixels
away and you compute the statistics of
has similar pixels are as a function of
distance they're less and less similar
so what does that mean is
because nearby pixels are likely to have
similar colors that means that when you
take a patch of pixels said father five
or eight by eight or something the type
of patch you're willing to observe is
very likely to be kind of a smoothly
varying color or maybe with an edge but
among all the possible combinations of
25 pixels the ones that you actually
observed in natural images is a tiny
subset what that means is that it's
advantageous to represent the content of
that patch by a vector with perhaps less
than 25 values that represent the
content of that patch is there an edge
is it uniform
what color is it you know things like
that right and that's basically what the
compositions in the first row you
accomplish on that are doing okay so yes
you have if you have local correlations
there is an advantage in detecting local
features that's what we observe in the
brain that's what congressional Nets are
doing the idea of locality if you feed a
commercial met with commuted pixels it's
not going to be able to do a good job at
recognizing your image images even if
the permutation is fixed right if we
connected that doesn't care about
permutations then the second
characteristics is that features are
important may appear anywhere on the
image so that's what justifies shared
weights
okay the correlation justifies local
connections the the fact that features
can appear anywhere that the statistics
of images or the signal is uniform means
that you need to have repeated feature
detectors for every location and that's
where shared weights come into play
it does certify the pudding because the
pudding is if you want invariance to
variations in the location of those
characteristic features and so if the
objects you're trying to recognize don't
change their nature by kind of being
slightly distorted then you want pooling
so people are his comrade for cancer
stuff image video text stitch so speech
actually is pretty sweet recognition
comm units are used a lot time series
prediction you know things like that and
you know biomedical image analysis so if
you want to you know analyze an MRI for
example MRI or CT scan is a 3d image as
humans we can't because we don't have a
good visualization technology we can't
really apprehend like you know
understand a kind of a 3d value but it's
really emotional image the ComNet is
fine you know if you did a 3d image and
it will deal with it that's a big
advantage because you don't have to go
through slices to kind of figure out the
object in the image and then the last
thing here at the bottom I don't know if
you guys know where hyperspectral image
images are so hyper spectral image is an
image where you know almost natural
color images I mean images that you
collect with a normal camera you get
three color components RGB but we can
build cameras with way more spectral
bands than this and that's particularly
the case for satellite imaging where
some cameras have many many spectral
bands going from infrared to ultraviolet
and that gives you a lot of information
about what you see in each pixel some
tiny animals I have small brains find it
easier to process hyper spectral images
of low resolution than high resolution
images with just three colors for
example the is particularly type of
shrimp right they have those beautiful
eyes and they have like 17 spectral
bands or something but super low
resolution and they have a tiny brain to
process it
okay that's one for today see you